## CINDY BOSIBORI

Bosibori.sydney@gmail.com · +254715712137

Motivated student taking a Computer Science degree. Experienced in Agile and Scrum environments. Well-organized and collaborative team player with strong communication and analytical abilities. Supports team administration, project coordination, design and programming needs. Fluent in various machine learning techniques in Natural Language Processing, Image Processing and Data Analysis. Conversant in PHP, Python, R, SQL, and other programming languages.

#### **EDUCATION**

# NAIROBI, KENYA | EXPECTED GRADUATION IN JUNE 2024 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE, STRATHMORE UNIVERSITY

- Dean's List 2020-2021 Academic Year
- Dean's List 2021-2022 Academic Year
- Dean's List 2022-2023 Academic Year

#### NAIROBI, KENYA | NOVEMBER 2019

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, THE KENYA HIGH SCHOOL

• 2019 Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (K.C.S.E) Grade A 84 points

#### **KAJIADO, KENYA | NOVEMBER 2015**

PRIMARY SCHOOL DIPLOMA, THORN TREE SCHOOL

• 2015 Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (K.C.P.E) Marks: 427/500

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### NAIROBI, KENYA | JANUARY 2023 – MARCH 2023 SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, AMT AFRICA

- Developed a facial recognition model using Deep Learning techniques as well as Local Binary Pattern Histograms for driver recognition.
- Incorporated the NATS publish-subscribe system to deploy the facial recognition model to the actual working environment.
- Developed an automatic road-sign reader system using Convolution Neural Networks.
- Grew my knowledge in Artificial Intelligence by taking short courses on Udemy as well as OpenCV.
- Pair programmed in a team of two along with the company CEO while developing the face recognizer as well as the road sign reader.
- Labelled around 6000 images that contained snapshots of different roads as well as the pedestrians, other vehicles, and road signs.

• Learned how to use various tools such as LabelImg for data labeling, and NATS for publishing topics and subscribing to them.

#### NAIROBI, KENYA | FEBRUARY 2022 – APRIL 2022

#### **VOLUNTEER, KENYA NATIONAL LIBRARY SERVICE**

- Greeted visitors, answered questions and made book recommendations across subjects and genres.
- Performed basic book reshelving and obtained items from book drop.
- Shelved books by subject according to Dewey Decimal System.
- Assisted patrons with finding and selecting book and materials using Online Public Access Catalog.
- Promoted library programs to obtain new signups for book clubs and youth reading contests.

### KAJIADO, KENYA | FEBRUARY 2020 – APRIL 2020

#### BANK TELLER, EQUITY BANK

- Built and strengthened customer relationships by leveraging excellent interpersonal and communication skills.
- Reconciled cash drawer and resolved discrepancies.
- Educated customers on use of banking website and mobile apps.
- Counted and packaged currency and coins.
- Provided customer records, account statements and copies of checks.
- Sold and cross-sold bank products to new and existing customers.
- Answered customer inquiries regarding account balances, transaction history, services charges and interest rates.
- Processed customer transactions promptly, minimizing wait times.
- Recognized needs and referred to appropriate representative or line of business for cross-sell or service opportunities.

#### SKILLS

- User Experience Design (UX)
- Back-End and Database Skills
- Avid Learner
- Time Management
- Scripting Languages: PHP, JavaScript
- Version Control Systems: Git, GitHub
- Machine Learning-facial recognition algorithms such as Dlib and CNN.
- Use Machine Learning in Biological Data Analysis
- Relational and non-relational database modelling.

- Working with distributed systems using NATS.
- Wireframing and Mock-up Design
- Front-End Programming: HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Extraction Transformation and Loading (ETL), Tableau.
- Biological database knowledge: GenBank, UniProt, and NCBI
- Fluent in Statistical methods and their integration in Machine Learning.
- SQL
- Machine Learning Natural Language Processing, actionable insights derivation.

#### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Worked on a facial recognition system that was able to recognize drivers that was deployed in an autonomous vehicle.
- Collaborated with a fellow student in the development of Helping Hands, an online fundraising platform for class 8 students transitioning to high school.
- Collaborated with team of 6 and resolved a user experience issue through restructuring of the Green Soko food delivery website.
- Led a team of 5 in a system analysis and design project through which we solved an ongoing issue and achieved an automated solution for inventory and cash flow management by introducing an automated cash book for a local Salon and Barber business.
- Successfully trained over 50 new customers over a one-month time period on how to use Equitel lines, perform bank transactions online using the Eazzy banking mobile application.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- IT Essentials, Cisco Networking Academy September 2020 December 2020
- CCNA Routing and Switching, Cisco Networking Academy January 2021 April 2021
- Foundations of Project Management, Coursera September 2022- October 2022
- Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design, Coursera September 2022 October 2022
- Foundations of Data Analytics, Coursera September 2022 November 2022
- Introduction to Cyber Security, Cisco Skills for All March 2023
- Networking Basics, Cisco Skills for All March 2023
- Networking Devices and Initial Configurations, Cisco Skills for All April 2023
- Endpoint Security, Cisco Skills for All April 2023
- Network Defense, Cisco Skills for All April 2023
- Certificate in Data Protection, Strathmore University (SU), the European Union (EU) and the German Development Agency (GIZ) December 2023